Finding Aid for the Recordings of June in Buffalo, 1975-1978, 1980
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Recordings of June in Buffalo, 1975-1978, 1980
Mus. Arc. 30
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Dept.
9 linear feet (64 reel to reel tapes, 179 audio compact discs, 58 DVDs)
The reformatted contents are on two sets of 79 CDs: one is labeled Service Copy, the other is labeled In-house Master. They contain audio files at 44.1kHz/16bit resolution. The 58 DVDs are labeled Preservation Master and contain WAV files at 96kHZ/24bit resolution. The John Cage lecture recordings were reformatted separately. They were reformatted as CD-R 44.1kHZ 16bit files and are contained on 3 sets of 7 CDs each: service copy, in-house master, and preservation master.
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The collection contains recordings of fifty-one of the fifty-three concerts presented at the June in Buffalo festival from 1975-1978 and in 1980. Approximately 216 works were recorded as well as some spoken introductions to works by their respective composers. The collection also contains recordings of three of the five lecture-seminars presented by John Cage during June in Buffalo 1975.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of State University of New York at Buffalo Music Dept.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
The original recordings were made on reel-to-reel tapes (all but two are 10 inch reels). The contents were digitized in 2007 onto CDs (service and in-house masters) and DVDs (preservation masters). Preservation wav files that match the original reel faces are named with roots that match the concert numbering, for example preservation files for the first concert are named JIB01_01.wav and JIB01_02.wav. The CD audio files on the Service CDs match the works presented at the concerts. Wav files were created from these files and are named using the work numbers listed in the container list with the addition of the suffix "sc" for service copy. For example, the first concert contains four works represented by files named JIB01_001_sc.wav, JIB01_002_sc.wav, JIB01_003_sc.wav, and JIB01_004_sc.wav. The preservation files and service files were also offloaded from the CDs and DVDs to the Institutional Repository.
Historical Note
The June in Buffalo festival of contemporary music was established by Morton Feldman in 1975. Morton Feldman joined the University at Buffalo Music Faculty in 1972. He was the Slee Professor, 1972-1973, Edgar Varèse Professor, 1975-1987, and the Director of the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts, 1976-1980. Feldman established the June in Buffalo festival in 1975 as a counterpart to the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts' successful Evenings for New Music concerts. The new festival was presented 1975-1978, and again in 1980, with a year off in 1979 when Feldman was on sabbatical. The festival was revived in 1986 by composer David Felder.
In addition to presenting concerts, Feldman's festival created a seminar environment in which student composers attended workshops where distinguished composers-in-residence rehearsed their works and gave lectures. Feldman also wanted to create a more intense listening experience by presenting programs that contained multiple works by a single composer. To that end, twelve works by John Cage were presented on the three concerts that opened the first festival in June 1975. Other single-composer programs were devoted to the works of Christian Wolff, Ralph Shapey, George Crumb, Lejaren Hiller, Nils Vigeland, Steve Reich, Charles Wuorinen, Henry Brant, Elliott Carter, Stefan Wolpe, Milton Babbitt, Lou Harrison, Earle Brown, and Aaron Copland. Works by earlier twentieth-century composers, including Ives, Schoenberg, Satie, Cowell, Webern, Berg, and Bártók were also presented on June in Buffalo programs. Three works received their United States premieres and five works received their world premieres at the festival. All concerts but one were held in what was then called Baird Hall (now Allen Hall) on what is now the South Campus. The June 1, 1976 concert was held at the Albright Knox Art Gallery in Buffalo.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains recordings for 51 of the 53 concerts that were presented 1975-1980 as part of the June in Buffalo concert series. It contains approximately 216 works. There are several instances of composers providing spoken introductions to their own works. The original recordings were made on reel-to-reel tapes (all but two are 10 inch reels). The contents were digitized in 2007 onto CDs (service and in-house masters) and DVDs (preservation masters).
Please note that this finding aid contains a description of the recorded concerts. However, the container list also reflects single works that were not recorded along with the rest of a concert program, such as when tapes were played of electronic works. Two complete concerts were not recorded: Concerts 7 and 34. Concert 7 (17 June 1975) consisted of performances of the two piano sonatas of Charles Ives. Piano sonata 1 was performed by Nils Vigeland; Piano sonata 2 was performed by Yvar Mikhashoff. Concert 34 (2 June 1978) featured performances by violinist Paul Zukofsky and pianist Ursula Oppens in John Cage's Cheap imitation (violin alone) and Six melodies, and Morton Feldman's Spring of Chosroes.
John Cage presented five lecture-seminars during June in Buffalo 1975. Of these, the collection has recordings of the three seminars presented June 4, 5, and 6. These seminars by visiting composers were an integral part of Morton Feldman's plan for the festival. The presentations by Cage are of interest because they are unscripted, spontaneous discussions rather than the prepared lectures he often presented. His interactions with the students and his digressions from reviewing their compositions provide glimpses of his personality and his aesthetics. The June 5 lecture is notable for containing Cage's dramatic response to a performance of his Song Books by the S.E.M. Ensemble on June 4.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series:
I. Concert recordings
II. John Cage Lectures
Container List
- Concert recordings, 1975-1978, 1980, I; Reel 1-2, 7-68
  The concert recordings are arranged in chronological order by concert. The descriptions pertain to entire concert programs. Reels 3-6 contain the John Cage lectures found in Series II.
  - June in Buffalo Concert 1: Music of John Cage, June 2, 1975, 2 10-inch reels of audio tape; Transferred to CD 1-2. Preservation master on DVD 1-2. (Box 1, Reel 1-2)
    Work number: JIB01_001
    Cage, John
    Third construction (1941)
    Performers: John Boudler, Donald Knaack, Jan Williams, Thomas Walsh, percussion
    Duration: 11:13
    Work number: JIB01_002
    Six melodies for violin and keyboard (1950)
    Performers: Benjamin Hudson, violin; Joseph Kubera, piano
    Duration: 12:58
    Work number: JIB01_003
    Music for toy piano (1960)
    Performers: Joseph Kubera, toy piano
    Duration: 9:01
    Work number: JIB01_004
    Book of music (1944)
    Performers: Joseph Kubera, Steve Radecke, prepared pianos
    Duration: 37:45
  - June in Buffalo Concert 2: Music of John Cage, June 4, 1975, 2 10-inch reels of audio tape; Transferred to CD 3-4. Preservation master on DVD 3-4. (Box 1, Reel 7-8)
    Work number: JIB02_001
    Atlas eclipticalis (1961-62)
    Realization by Jan Williams.
    Performers: Eberhard Blum, flute; Benjamin Hudson, violin; Donald Knaack, John Boudler, Jan Williams, percussion; Ralph Jones, electronics; Suzy Hawkins, conductor
    Duration: 39:48
    Work number: JIB02_002
    Song books (1970)
    Performers: S.E.M. Ensemble; Petr Kotík, flute, director; Julius Eastman, voice; Judith Martin, synthesizer; Jan Williams, percussion
    Duration: 1:03:04
  - June in Buffalo Concert 3: Music of John Cage, June 6, 1975, 2 10-inch reels of audio tape; Transferred CD 5-6. Preservation master on DVD 5-6. (Box 1, Reel 9-10)
    First five works performed simultaneously for a total duration of 45:06.
    Work number: JIB03_001A
    45' for a speaker (1954)
    Performers: Michael Christopher, speaker
    Work number: JIB03_001B
    27' 10.554 for a percussionist (1956)
    Performers: Jan Williams, percussion
    Work number: JIB03_001C
    34' 46.776 for a pianist (1954)
    Performers: Joseph Kubera, piano
    Work number: JIB03_001D
    26' 1.1499 for a string player (1955)
    Performers: Benjamin Hudson, violin
    Work number: JIB03_001E
    Solo for flute (1957)
    Performers: Eberhard Blum, flute
    Work number: JIB03_002
    Etcetera (1972-73)
    Performers: Eberhard Blum, flute; Mary Sue Wells, violoncello; Benjamin Hudson, violin; James Kasprowicz, trombone; John Boudler, Donald Knaack, Jan Williams, percussion; Ralph Jones, electronics; Daniel J. Zelonky, Windsor Viney, Samuel Magrill, Marten Ingle, Suzy Hawkins, Ron Kuivila, Mary Michels, percussion; Michael Christopher (Quartets), Robert Brainerd (Duets), Andrew Stiller (Trios), conductors
    Duration: 1:01:20
  - June in Buffalo Concert 4: Music of Christian Wolff, Earle Brown, Morton Feldman, and John Cage, June 11, 1975, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 7. Preservation master on DVD 7. (Box 1, Reel 11)
    Work number: JIB04_001
    Wolff, Christian, 1934-
    Snowdrop (1970)
    Performers: Joseph Kubera, piano; Steve Radecke, organ; Nils Vigeland, harpsichord
    Duration: 9:35
    Work number: JIB04_002
    Brown, Earle, 1926-2002
    Corroboree (1963-64)
    Performers: Joseph Kubera, Steve Radecke, Nils Vigeland, pianos
    Duration: 13:00
    Work number: JIB04_003
    Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987
    Piece for four pianos (1957)
    Performers: Morton Feldman, Steve Radecke, Joseph Kubera, Nils Vigeland, pianos
    Duration: 6:00
    Work number: JIB04_004
    Winter music (1957)
    Performers: Mark Brooks, James Calabrese, Tom Constanten, Peter Gena, Neal Hatch, Benjamin Hudson, Margaret Knaack, Joseph Kubera, Steve Radecke, Casey Sokol, Yong Sook Won, pianos
    Duration: 30:00
  - June in Buffalo Concert 5: Music of Earle Brown, June 13, 1975, 1 10-inch reel and 1 7-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 8-9. Preservation master on DVD 8-9. (Box 1, Reel 12-13)
    Introductory remarks by Earle Brown (4:55).
    Work number: JIB05_001
    Novara (1962)
    Performers: Joseph Kubera, piano; Eberhard Blum, flute; Ron Byerly, trumpet; Gary Hatt, bass clarinet; Benjamin Hudson, Sue Harbison, violins; Diane Williams, viola; Mary Sue Wells, violoncello; Marten Ingle, double bass; Jan Williams, conductor
    Duration: 16:34
    Work number: JIB05_002
    Hodograph (1959)
    Performers: Joseph Kubera, keyboards; Donald Knaack, percussion; Eberhard Blum, flute
    Duration: 4:38
    Work number: JIB05_003
    Times five (1963)
    Performers: Eberhard Blum, flute; James Kasprowicz, trombone; Benjamin Hudson, violin; Mary Sue Wells, violoncello; Diana Landes, harp; Jan Williams, conductor
    Duration: 15:08
    Additional spoken comments by Brown (2:25).
    Work number: JIB05_004
    December (1952)
    Performers: Donald Knaack, Joseph Kubera, Eberhard Blum, penny whistles, kazoos
    Duration: 7:08
    Work number: JIB05_005
    New piece (1971)
    Performers: Benjamin Hudson, Sue Harbison, violins; Diane Williams, viola; Mary Sue Wells, violoncello; Marten Ingle, double bass; Eberhard Blum, flute; Gary Hatt, bass clarinet; William Lynn Johnston, saxophone; Jonathan Adler, bassoon; Ron Byerly, trumpet; James Kasprowicz, trombone; Donald Knaack, John Boudler, percussion; Earle Brown, conductor
    Duration: 7:00
    Work number: JIB05_006
    Syntagm III (1970)
    Performers: Eberhard Blum, flute; Gary Hatt, bass clarinet; Diana Landes, harp; Benjamin Hudson, violin; Joseph Kubera, piano; Donald Knaack, percussion; Mary Sue Wells, violoncello; Earle Brown, conductor
    Duration: 13:58
  - June in Buffalo Concert 6: Music of Earle Brown, Morton Feldman, Lejaren Hiller, June 16, 1975, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 10-11. Preservation master on DVD 10-11. (Box 1, Reel 14)
    Work number: JIB06_001
    Quartet, strings (1965)
    Performers: Benjamin Hudson, Carol Zeavin, violins; Maureen Gallagher, viola; Dana Rusinak, violoncello
    Duration: 8:35
    Work number: JIB06_002
    Three pieces for string quartet (1954-55)
    Duration: 13:39
    Work number: JIB06_003
    Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994
    Quartet, strings, no. 6, (1972)
    Duration: 23:44
    Work number: JIB06_004
    Three rituals for two percussionists
    Performers: Jan Williams, Donald Knaack, percussion; Peter Gena, technical assistance
    Included film by Roberta Friedman and Grahame Weinbren.
    Duration: 36:02
    Encore
    Reich, Steve, 1936-
    Clapping music
    Performers: Jan Williams, Dennis Kahle, hands
    Duration: 2:36
  - June in Buffalo Concert 8: Music of Christian Wolff, June 18, 1975, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 12. Preservation master on DVD 12. (Box 1, Reel 15)
    Preceded by ambient sound (ca. 3:15) and introductory remarks by Christian Wolff (7:26).
    Work number: JIB08_001
    Changing the system (1972-73)
    Performers: Jonathan Adler, bassoon; Eberhard Blum, bass flute, percussion; James Calabrese, assorted percussion, text; Michael Christopher, assorted percussion, text; George Cisneros, marimba; Kyle Gann, percussion, text; John Green, percussion, text; Gary Hatt, bass clarinet; clarinet, percussion; Benjamin Hudson, violin; Marten Ingle, double bass, percussion; Ralph Jones, text, trumpet; James Kasprowicz, trombone; Donald Knaack, vibraphone, percussion; Joseph Kubera, piano, percussion; Ron Kuivila, assorted percussion, text; Sam Magrill, percussion, text; Steve Radecke, harmonica, percussion; Casey Sokol, piano, percussion; Windsor Viney, assorted percussion, text; Christian Wolff, flute, percussion
    Duration: 60:22
  - June in Buffalo Concert 9: Music of Christian Wolff, June 20, 1975, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 13. Preservation master on DVD 13. (Box 1, Reel 16)
    Work number: JIB09_001
    Exercises and songs (1973-74)
    Performers: Eberhard Blum, flute; Benjamin Hudson, violin; Marten Ingle, Donald Knaack, percussion; Joseph Kubera, organ; James Kasprowicz, trombone; Steve Radecke, piano; Christian Wolff, melodien; Joan Collopy, voice
    Duration: 62:03
  - June in Buffalo Concert 10: Music of Iannis Xenakis, June 1, 1976, 2 10-inch reels of audio tape; Transferred to CD 14. Preservation master on DVD 14. (Box 1, Reel 17-18)
    Work number: JIB10_001
    Xenakis, Iannis, 1922-2001
    Persephassa
    Performers: Donald Knaack, John Boudler, David Kayne, Timothy Leaphart, Robert Mahoney, Will Rogers, percussion; Jan Williams, conductor
    Duration: 25:18
    Work number: JIB10_002
    Eonta
    Performers: Joseph Kubera, piano; Charles Gleaves, Gerald Soffer, Charles Lirette, David Kuehn, trumpets; Lon Gormley, James Kasprowicz, Donald Miller, trombones; Jan Williams, conductor
    Duration: 20:04
  - June in Buffalo Concert 11: Music of Soegijo, Globokar, Xenakis, Kagel, June 2, 1976, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 15. Preservation master on DVD 15. (Box 1, Reel 19)
    Work number: JIB11_001
    Soegijo, Paul Gutama
    Saih I (1970)
    Performers: Eberhard Blum, bass flute
    Duration: 13:26
    Work number: JIB11_002
    Globokar, Vinko, 1934-
    Discours III (1969)
    Performers: Nora Post, oboes
    Duration: 11:38
    Work number: JIB11_003
    Psappha
    Performers: Donald Knaack, percussion
    Duration: 16:30
    United States premiere
    Work number: JIB11_004
    Kagel, Mauricio
    Atem (1970)
    Performers: Eberhard Blum, flute; Jan Williams, mime
    Duration: 14:37
  - June in Buffalo Concert 12: Music of Xenakis, Feldman, Hiller, Crumb, June 3, 1976, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 16. Preservation master on DVD 16. (Box 1, Reel 20)
    Work number: JIB12_001
    ST/4
    Performers: David Harrington, Richard Balkin, violins; Aliza Appel, viola; Walter Gray, violoncello
    Duration: 16:59
    Work number: JIB12_002
    Structures for string quartet
    Duration: 7:22
    Work number: JIB12_003
    Illiac suite
    Duration: 18:42
    Work number: JIB12_004
    Crumb, George
    Black angels
    Duration: 24:58
  - June in Buffalo Concert 13: Music of Morton Feldman, June 4, 1976, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 17. Preservation master on DVD 17. (Box 1, Reel 21)
    Work number: JIB13_001
    Instruments I
    Performers: Eberhard Blum, flute; Nora Post, oboe; James Kasprowicz, trombone; Joseph Kubera, celeste; Jan Williams, percussion
    Duration: 23:16
    Work number: JIB13_002
    Instruments II
    Performers: Eberhard Blum, flute; Nora Post, oboe; Gary Hatt, clarinet; David Kuehn, trumpet; James Kasprowicz, trombone; Don Harry, tuba; Suzanne Thomas, harp; Joseph Kubera, piano; Donald Knaack, percussion; Makoto Michii, double bass; Jan Williams, conductor
    Duration: 20:12
  - June in Buffalo Concert 14: American songs performed by Winifred Simpson and Yvar Mikhashoff, June 7, 1976, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 18. Preservation master on DVD 18. (Box 1, Reel 22)
    Presented in the form of a salon entertainment with comments provided by Winifred Simpson about the music between the songs.
    Work number: JIB14_001
    MacDowell, Edward, 1860-1908
    To a water lily
    Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano
    Applause and introductory remarks (0:52).
    Work number: JIB14_002
    Beach, H. H. A., Mrs., 1867-1944
    Year's at the spring
    Performers: Winifred Simpson, soprano; Yvar Mikhashoff, piano
    Duration: 1:02
    Applause and introductory remarks (0:47).
    Work number: JIB14_003
    Merry maiden spring
    Duration: 1:18
    Applause and introductory remarks (0:54).
    Work number: JIB14_004
    Cadman, Charles Wakefield, 1881-1946
    From the land of sky-blue water
    Duration: 2:16
    Applause and introductory remarks (0:38).
    Work number: JIB14_005
    Chadwick, George Whitefield, 1854-1931
    Nocturne
    Duration: 1:37
    Applause and introductory remarks (2:19).
    Work number: JIB14_006
    Gottschalk, Louis Moreau, 1829-1869
    Last hope
    Duration: 4:25
    Applause and introductory remarks (1:01).
    Work number: JIB14_007
    Work, Henry C. (Henry Clay), 1832-1884
    Father, dear father, come home with me now (Come home, father)
    Duration: 4:46
    Applause and introductory remarks (0:33).
    Work number: JIB14_008
    Von Tilzer, Harry, 1872-1946
    Bird in a gilded cage
    Duration: 4:01
    Applause and introductory remarks (0:17).
    Work number: JIB14_009
    Romberg, Sigmund, 1887-1951
    Will you remember
    Duration: 2:05
    Applause and introductory remarks (1:32).
    Work number: JIB14_010
    Edwards, Gus, 1879-1945
    Pan, Pan, Pan
    Duration: 1:15
    Applause and introductory remarks (0:50).
    Work number: JIB14_011
    Loomis, Harvey Worthington, 1865-1930
    Violet fan
    Performers: Winifred Simpson, reciter; Yvar Mikhashoff, piano
    Duration: 6:18
    Applause and introductory remarks (0:45).
    Work number: JIB14_012
    I'm after Madame Tetrazzini's job
    Duration: 2:57
    Applause and introductory remarks (1:23).
    Work number: JIB14_013
    Stromberg, John
    Come down ma evenin' star
    Duration: 2:48
    Applause and introductory remarks (0:32).
    Work number: JIB14_014
    Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924
    Italian street song
    Duration: 1:43
    Applause (0:22).
    Work number: JIB14_015
    Harris, Chas. (Charles Kassell), 1867-1930
    After the ball
    Duration: 2:22
  - June in Buffalo Concert 15: Music of Charles Ives, June 8, 1976, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 19-20. Preservation master on DVD 19. (Box 1, Reel 23)
    Work number: JIB15_001
    Ives, Charles, 1874-1954
    Sonata, violin, piano, no. 1
    Performers: Paul Zukofsky, violin; Gilbert Kalish, piano
    Duration: 28:47
    Work number: JIB15_002
    Sonata, violin, piano, no. 2
    Duration: 15:52
    Announcement about the order of movements in next work (0:21)
    Work number: JIB15_003
    Sonata, violin, piano, no. 3
    Duration: 36:07
    Work number: JIB15_004
    Sonata, violin, piano, no. 4
    Duration: 12:23
    Work number: JIB15_005
    Largo
    Duration: 6:48
  - June in Buffalo Concert 16: Music of Lejaren Hiller, June 9, 1976, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 21. Preservation master on DVD 20. (Box 1, Reel 24)
    Work number: JIB16_001
    Algorithms II, version 3 (1972)
    Performers: Jay Hersher, flute; Gary Hatt, clarinet; Andrew Stiller, bassoon; Suzanne Thomas, harp; Donald Knaack, John Boudler, percussion; Linda Cummiskey, violin; Don Reinfeld, violoncello; Makoto Michii, double bass; Jan Williams, conductor
    Duration: 4:56
    Premiere performance
    Work number: JIB16_002
    Algorithms I, version 2 (1968)
    Duration: 6:01
    Buffalo premiere
    Work number: JIB16_003
    Algorithms II [or III?], version 4 (1972) on two tracks
    Duration: 10:24
    Work number: JIB16_004
    Malta for tuba and tape (1975)
    Performers: Don Harry, tuba
    Duration: 22:55
    Tape realized by the composer
    Work number: JIB16_005
    Portfolio for diverse performers and tape (1974)
    Performers: Jay Hersher, flute; Donald Knaack, Jan Williams, percussion; Nora Post, oboe; Linda Cummiskey, violin; Gary Hatt, clarinet; James Kasprowicz, trombone; Andrew Stiller, bassoon; Joseph Kubera, piano; Ned Sublette, guitar; Walter Gajewski, electronics
    Duration: 22:27
  - June in Buffalo Concert 17: Music of Schoenberg, Webern, Boulez, June 10, 1976, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 22. Preservation master on DVD 21. (Box 1, Reel 25)
    Work number: JIB17_001
    Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951
    Drei Klavierstücke, op. 11 (1909)
    Performers: Stephen Manes, piano
    Duration: 14:15
    Work number: JIB17_002
    Webern, Anton, 1883-1945
    Variationen fur Klavier, op. 27 (1936)
    Duration: 5:29
    Work number: JIB17_003
    Boulez, Pierre, 1925-
    Sonata, piano, no. 3
    Duration: 12:49
    Work number: JIB17_004
    Sonata, piano, no. 2
    Duration: 34:52
  - June in Buffalo Concert 18: Music of Steve Reich, June 11, 1976, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 23. Preservation master on DVD 22. (Box 1, Reel 26)
    Work number: JIB18_001
    Clapping music (1972)
    Performers: Donald Knaack, Steve Reich, hands
    Duration: 5:27
    Work number: JIB18_002
    Piano phase (1967)
    Performers: John Newell, Steve Reich, pianos
    Duration: 14:44
    Work number: JIB18_003
    Drumming (1971). Part 3
    Performers: John Boudler, Steve Reich, Tom Walsh, Jan Williams, glockenspiels; Jay Hersher, piccolo
    Duration: 9:44
    Work number: JIB18_004
    Music for pieces of wood (1973)
    Performers: John Boudler, Donald Knaack, Steve Reich, Tom Walsh, Jan Williams, tuned claves
    Duration: 11:52
    Concert concluded with audio tape played of Steve Reich's Music for 18 Musicians, which was not recorded.
  - June in Buffalo Concert 19: Music of George Crumb, June 14, 1976, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 24-25. Preservation master on DVD 23. (Box 1, Reel 27)
    Work number: JIB19_001
    Makrokosmos (volume I)
    Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, amplified piano
    Duration: 38:23
    Work number: JIB19_002
    Makrokosmos (volume II)
    Duration: 39:14